Guide to the Tom Rose Ephemera collection documenting the electronics industry, 1964 - 1988
Department of Special Collections
Rose, Tom, collector. Ephemera collection documenting the electronics industry,
1964 - 1988
M1304
Rose, Tom
.75 linear ft. (1.5 manuscript boxes)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
The collection includes product catalogs, brochures, flyers, and handouts from electronics firms throughout the United States, as well as from U.S. subsidiaries of international electronics firms. The majority of the materials document electronic sound and data recording technology.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Tom Rose, 2002.
Biography
Tom Rose worked as a Design Engineer at Dynasonic Systems of Dallas, Texas. He held the same position at Continental Electronics, also located in Dallas.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
The collection includes product catalogs, brochures, flyers, and handouts from electronics firms throughout the United States, as well as from U.S. subsidiaries of international electronics firms. The majority of the materials document electronic sound and data recording technology.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Electronics industry.; Science -- History.
Collection Contents
- 3M (Box 1, Folder 1)
- A.R. Vetterca. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Accurate Sound Corp.1987 - 1988, 1 item (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Arvin / Echo ca. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Astro-Science Corp.ca. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Beaver Research Corp.ca. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Borg Warner Corp.ca. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Brainconca. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Cipher Data Products, Inc.ca. 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Consolidated Electrodynamicsca. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Cybertronics, Inc.ca. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Dartexca. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Data Laboratories, Inc.ca. 1987 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Defense Electronics, Inc.ca. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Digi-Data Corp.ca. 1968 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- DMI (Data Memory, Inc.)ca. 1969 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- EMI Technologies, Inc.ca. 1981 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Fairchild Winston Research Corp.ca. 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- General Kinetics, Inc.1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Genisco Technology Corp.ca. 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Geotechnical Corp.ca. 1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Gould Electronics & Electrical Products1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Hewlett-Packard (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Honeywell. Test Instrument Division (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Kennedy Co.1965 - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Kinelogic Corp.1964 - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- KRS Electronics1964 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Leach Corp. Controls Division1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Lufkin (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Miles Reproducer Co., Inc. (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Miller-Stephenson Chemical Co., Inc. (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Pacer Co. (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Philips Electronic Instruments (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Philips Test & Measuring Instruments, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Pickering & Co. (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Potter Instrument Co., Inc. (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Precision Data, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Precision Instrument Co. (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Racal Recorders (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Ralph M. Parsons Electronics Co. (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Raymond Engineering Laboratory, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 1)
- S. Himmelstein and Co. (Box 2, Folder 2)
- S-I Electronics, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Sabre Systems, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Sanders Associates, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Sangamo Electric Co. (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Scientific Data Systems (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Sony Corporation of America (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Tandberg (Box 2, Folder 9)
- TEAC [1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 10)
- TEAC [2 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Technical Measurement Corp. (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Texas Instruments, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 13)
- UDAC (Universal Data Acquisition Co.) (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Whittaker Corp. (Box 2, Folder 15)
Related Collections
Hewlett-Packard Company
Hewlett-Packard Ephemera Collection, 1957-1994 M1306
An online guide to the Tom Rose Ephemera Collection Documenting the Electronics Industry,1964-1988 is available as an XML document at: http://www-sul.stanford.edu/depts/spc/xml/m1306.xml and as an HTML document at: http://www.oac.cdlib.org/dynaweb/ead/stanford/mss/m1306/
Silicon Valley Ephemera Collection M0443
An online guide to the Silicon Valley Ephemera Collection is available as an XML document at: http://www-sul.stanford.edu/depts/spc/xml/m0443.xml and as an HTML document at: http://www.oac.cdlib.org/dynaweb/ead/stanford/mss/m0443/